Mennatullah Mohamed Yosry

Back-end Developer

Phone: 01017279726 | LinkedIn: MennatullahMohamedYosry | GitHub: MennaYosry | G-mail: yosrymenna7@gmail.com

Profile Summary

A well-motivated developer, with a high team working ,communication and problem solving skills, and great flexibility for different work environments ,I am interested in applying for a position as my skills are studying background matched with your requirements.

In my previous role as a Coding Instructor 3C Academy, I developed, maintained and taught kids (6 - 18 years old) CPP (basic skills - Data Structure - Algorithms " ex: Binary search - Prefix Sum - Graphs "), introduction to AI in Python and interactive web applications using Html, CSS and JavaScript.

And role Team leader Mentor in IEEE O6U Community WEB Society. I am proficient in a variety of programming languages, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, C++, C#, PHP, Python, Java, laravel framework, ASP.Net framework, SQL Server and MySQL.

I am eager to learn more about any open positions that you may have and I am confident that I would be a valuable asset to your team. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Experience

External instructor , <u>YAT Learning Center.</u>

(May,2024 - present)

- Administrating SQL Server Course .

Coding Instructor , MY Academy .

(Apr,2024 - present)

Coding Instructor , <u>AMS Academy</u>.

(Feb , 2024 -present)

Coding Instructor , <u>3C Academy</u> .

(Oct ,2023 - present)

- Adding hands-on experience to Egyptian students using JavaScript ,HTML , CSS and AI using Python.
- Teaching and diving into basics programming , Data structure and Algorithms using C++ and introduction to Al and Machine Learning for Olympiad Al in KSA.
- Back-end , <u>PureSoft.Co</u> .

(Jun, 2023 - Sep, 2023)

Back-end , <u>Motoon</u> Company .

(Aug ,2022 - May ,2023)

Education

Faculty of Computer and Artificial Intelligence, Helwan University, Medical Informatics Department.

(GPA 3.11, B+)

(2019 - 2023)

Courses

- SQL Server , DataCamp . Agile Methodology . C# OOP , Metigator Academy .
- Restfull API , Techno U. PHP Laravel , <u>Tech Time</u> .
- Git and GitHub Practical Course , Udemy .
- The PHP 8 Learning Guide [Edition 2022] , Udemy .

<u>Skills</u>

Soft Skills: - Problem-solving skills. - Leadership skills. - Work under pressure - Ability to work in team. - Agile Mindset.

Technical Skills:

- HTML . - CSS . - JavaScript . - CPP . - Python.

- C# . - PHP . - Git/GitHub . - OOP . -MYSQL

- Microsoft SQL Server . - BootStrap Foundation . - ASP.NET Core

- .NET Framework . - SOLID Principles . - RESTFUL API

- Design Patterns . - Entity Framework (ORMs) . - LARAVEL Framework.

- Linq - Unit Testing . - WCF Framework .

Projects Samples

- Clinic System

Degree: 98% (A+)

Graduation Project (Team Work)

Back-end: Laravel Framework, Restful API (Postman, MYSQL) - Developed by me

Machine Learning: Python for pathology detection model

Front-end: ReactJS

- Patient Form WCF Client-server sides

Technologies: WCF Framework, Windows form.

- Weather App

Framework: .Net C# (Restful API)

- Articles System

Technologies: ASP.NET Core, SQL SERVER, Entity Framework, MS Test, Bootstrap Foundation

- School Register Courses System

Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, Factory Design Pattern, Dependency Injection Design Pattern, SQL

SERVER

- Ideas Table Web App

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Native PHP, MySQL

Responsibilities:

Implemented features for adding new ideas (title and description).

Developed functionality to display all ideas in a main table.

- Blog System

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Native PHP, PDO, MySQL

Responsibilities:

Implemented user, client, and admin functionality for registration, login, and logout.

Enabled users to add blogs and comment on existing ones.

- ProductsTech System

Technologies: Native PHP, HTML, CSS

Responsibilities:

Admin capabilities to delete products and users.

User functionalities include adding products (with description and image) and commenting.

Implemented user registration, login, and logout.

- Students List

Technologies: Laravel Framework (Blade System), MySQL

Responsibilities:

Simple CRUD project aiding in learning basics.

Feel free to customize the descriptions and details based on your specific contributions and experiences within each project.

Volunteering

Team Leader, Web Team IEEE 6th, October University CS Society. (Oct, 2022 - April, 2023)

Member , <u>Helwan ICPC Community</u> . (Nov ,2020 - Jun ,2023)

Member , Web team IEEE AL-Azhar University. (Jun ,2022 - Oct ,2022)

<u>Languages</u> - Arabic . - English .